<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tourmate</string>
    <string name="txt_bandarban">The India - Myanmar Sabroom - Coxs Bazar railway link has been proposed to connect Sabroom - Khargachari - Rangamati - Bandarban - Satkania - Coxs Bazar and another rail link connecting Bandarban to Tuipang, India.Bandarban lies, by bus, eight hours away from Dhaka, two hours from Chittagong and three hours from Coxs Bazar. It is also possible to get there by a six-hour bus ride from Rangamati. The Buddha Dhatu Jadi, the Buddhist temple in Bangladesh, located in Balaghata, 4km from the town. This place attracts many tourists every year. This Theravada Buddhist temple is made completely in the style of South-East Asia and houses the second largest statue of the Buddha in Bangladesh. The waterfall named Shoilo Propat at Milanchari is another place tourists like to visit. The numerous Buddhist temples, known as kyang in local tongue, and bhihars in the town include the highly notable the Rajvihar (royal vihar) at Jadipara and the Ujanipara Bhihar. Bawm villages around Chimbuk, and Mru villages a little further off, are also lie within a days journey from the town. Prantik Lake, Jibannagar and Kyachlong Lake are some more places of interest. Boat ride on the river Shangu is one of the main attractions here for tourists. </string>

    <string name="txt_cox_bazar">The beach in Coxs Bazar is the main attraction of the town with an unbroken length of 150km also termed the "longest natural unbroken sea beach" in the world. There are several 3 stars and 5 star hotels provide the exclusive beachside area with accessories for the tourist. Visitors in other hotels visit Laboni beach which is the area of the beach closest to the town. Other than the beach there are several places of interest near the town which can easily be visited from the town center</string>
    <string name="txt_khagrachari">Khagrachhari is the natural wild beauty of Bangladesh. Here you can visit the tribal lifestyle of Chakmas in Khagrachari. You can also visit Alu tila hill. Approximately 100 meters long a very dark Cave is the mysterious beauty of Alu tila hill. Khagrachari hill district (east-southern region of Bangladesh) is full of hills and waterfalls. The people of hilly areas usually live on the top of the hills. The major problem for them is the crisis of drinking water on such height. The people in the hill areas are still deprived and don not have the civil facilities such as sanitation, proper education and economy. Sapchari waterfall is situated in Khagrachari Hill district and about 115 km north from Chittagong town. The waterfall is near to the sapchari village and is emerged out Alutila Hill Range situated by the Chengi River. One may go to Khagrachari by bus from chittagong city. From Khagrachari bus terminal using rickshaw or some other means s/he may reach at Khabangpujjya. Then across the Chengi river the Sapchari village is situated. In the south of the Sapchari village the Sapchari waterfall is located. The landscape is very charismatic and the whole view of Khagrachari town can be observed from the top of the waterfall.Some government and private rest house, hotels, motels and resorts are available in Khagrachari. There are some bus services to go Dhaka to Khagrachari. BRTC, Dolphin Paribahan, S. Alam Services are the direct bus services from Dhaka to Rangamati. Traveler will find the calm and quiet environment in Khagrachari.</string>
    <string name="txt_kuakata">Kuakata is a place of pilgrimage for Hindu and Buddhist communities. Innumerable devotees arrive here at the festivals of Rush Purnima and Maghi Purnima. On these occasions the pilgrims take holy baths at the bay and participate in the traditional fairs.[1] One may visit a 100-year-old Buddhist temple where the statue of Goutama Buddha and two 200-year-old wells are located. The town Kuakata has sea beach named Kuakata Beach. Many tourists visit the place to see the beach although it hasn’t international recognition like Coxs Bazar Beach but it is popular in Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="txt_rangamati">Rangamati is located in the Chittagong Division. It is bordered by the Tripura state of India to the north, Bandarban District to the south, Mizoram State of India and Chin State of Myanmar to the east, and Khagrachari and Chittagong Districts to the west. Rangamati is the only district in Bangladesh with international borders with two countries: India and Myanmar. Rangamati was a contesting ground for the kings of Tripura and Arakan. It was known as Reang/Riang Country before East India Company came. This region came under the Mughal Empire after the Muslim invasion in 1566.[5] In 1737, Sher Mosta Khan, a tribal leader, took refuge with the Mughals. After this the Chakma settlement began along with various other settlements of varying ethnicity. From 1760 to 1761. </string>
    <string name="txt_saint_martin">Millennia ago, the island used to be an extension of the Teknaf peninsula, but at a later time some portion of this peninsula got submerged and thus the southernmost part of the aforementioned peninsula became an island, and was disconnected from the Bangladesh mainland. The first settlement started 250 years ago, in 18th century, by Arabian merchants who named the island Jazira. During British occupation the island was named after the then Deputy Commissioner of Chittagong Mr. Martin as St. Martin Island. Likely because one or more of the Arabs were Saint and whose name could not be identified. Local names of the island are "Narikel jinjira" which means Coconut Island, and "Daruchini Dwip" which means "Cinnamon island". It is the only coral island in Bangladesh. </string>
    <string name="txt_sajek">Sajek Valley is one of the most popular tourist spots in Bangladesh situated among the hills of the Kasalong range of mountains in Sajek union, Baghaichhari Upazila in Rangamati District.[3] The valley is 2,000 feet (610m) above sea level.[4] Sajek Valley is known as the Queen of Hills and Roof of Rangamati. Sajek is a union located in the north of Chittagong Hill Tracts. Its under Baghaichori Upazila in Rangamati hill district, it is situated 67 kilometres (42mi) north-east from Khagrachhari town and 95 kilometres (59mi) north from Rangamati city. The border of Bangladesh and Mizoram of India is 8 kilometres (5.0mi) east from Sajek. </string>
    <string name="txt_sitakunda">Sitakunda or Sitakunda Town is an administrative centre and the sole municipality of Sitakunda Upazila in Chattogram District, located in Chattogram Division, Bangladesh. Sitakunda is famous for the Chandranath Temple and Hindus temple. There is a hot water spring 5 km to the north of the town. </string>
    <string name="txt_sundarban">Sundarbans is a mangrove area in the delta formed by the confluence of the Padma, Brahmaputra and Meghna Rivers in the Bay of Bengal. It spans the area from the Baleswar River in Bangladeshs division of Khulna to the Hooghly River in Indias state of West Bengal.</string>
    <string name="txt_sylhet">Sylhet is a city in eastern Bangladesh, on the Surma River. Its known for its Sufi shrines, like the ornate tomb and mosque of 14th-century saint Hazrat Shah Jalal, now a major pilgrimage site near Dargah Gate. The tiny Museum of Rajas contains belongings of the local folk poet Hasan Raja. A 3-domed gateway stands at the 17th-century Shahi Eidgah, a huge open-air hilltop mosque built by Emperor Aurangzeb.</string>
    <string name="txt_tanguar_haor">Tanguar Haor located in the Dharmapasha and Tahirpur upazilas of Sunamganj District in Bangladesh, is a unique wetland ecosystem of national importance and has come into international focus. The area of Tanguar Haor including 46 villages within the haor is about 100 square kilometres (39sqmi) of which 2,802.36 ha2 is wetland. It is the source of livelihood for more than 40,000 people. Bangladesh declared it an Ecologically Critical Area in 1999 considering its critical condition as a result of overexploitation of its natural resources.</string>
</resources>